[Music]
toffee fee
if you don't know what they are then
you're seriously missing out a great
little suite
had them for years ever since i was a
kid i try and pick them up whenever i
can
this little box is about a pound but um
you know might be different price
wherever you are
but there seems to be a bit of a
shortage during lockdown so took the
opportunity and grabbed some from the
supermarket
what exactly are they well according to
the pack they are a hazelnut and caramel
with
creamy nougat and nougat chocolate
bit of an oversimplification but
essentially that's what they are
i created this flavor quite a while ago
actually and
it was just enough using off-the-shelf
ingredients so you can make this with
some very simple things just pick up a
supermarket a hazelnut milk chocolate
and a can adultery
those along with your standard milk
cream and sugar that will get you
in this ballpark so how exactly do you
make it
[Music]
it really is quite a simple recipe so
add your milk cream of sugar
into the smallest possible pan you can
heat it extremely gently and then try
and combine
the dulce de leche without spilling it
all over the cooker once that's well
incorporated try and transfer it to a
slightly bigger vessel
without spilling it everywhere again and
chill it down you can do
this in a nice bath or in the fridge
it's completely up to you
now once the base is chilling chop up
your hazelnut milk chocolate and store
it in the fridge or freezer
ready we've used lint as it's just
bloody good chocolate but
you can use whatever's available once
chilled
remove the fridge and add two tabs of
milk powder you know me i love my milk
powder
leave it for 20 minutes and then finally
mix it again before churning
now as this is a high sugar recipe it
will take a little bit longer to churn
so make sure you don't overfill the
machine as you want to cut that freezing
time as much as possible
once the base is ready remove it from
the machine and start layering it
with your remaining dulce de leche and
your hazelnut chocolate
finally when it's done pop it in the
freezer until you're ready to eat it
the toffee ice cream has been in the
freezer overnight i'm gonna grab it and
get some out on the plate and
show you what it looks like
another great tub by my wife she's
really good at these
so let's scoop
oh yeah
the texture alone of this is is
incredible i mean it's like i said it's
a high sugar ice cream
so if it doesn't scoop straight at the
top you've done something wrong
it does take a little bit longer to trim
because of that because the sugar has
suppressed a freezing point
which means it takes a little bit longer
to churn but
the result is quite incredible so
you've got a lovely
combination of
caramel or dolce de leche ice cream
it is truly incredible the ice cream is
super smooth the caramel flavor comes
through
really really nicely that dolce electro
swirl is just
it's heaven you get that bite of the
chocolate and hazelnut come through
it's just enough chocolate you don't
want the chocolate to overpower you
could put like a chocolate cracker top
over this if you wanted to
but there is nothing about this ice
cream that doesn't shout
toffee
it's one of those things that
i always just buy a pack they're i think
they're a pound for that size pack
they're an incredible flavor combination
and
just get that on this it's not exactly
the same
but it really shouts out toffee v when
you try it
i do hope you try this recipe lots of
other people have tried in the past and
it gets
great feedback every time so if you do
like and comment below and if you're
watching this you're not a subscriber
just hit that subscribe button click the
little bell as well really helps out
next video is a recreation ben jerry's
one of their new flavors to cookie dough
twist
so hope you stick around for that one
thanks so much for watching see you next
time
[Music]